Good evening, Tamura-san.
Dobry wieczór, Tamura-san.
Yes, the strongest signal we are capable of emanating is our intent to kill
Zamiar zabójstwa to najsilniejszy sygnał, jaki możemy wysłać.
or just hostility.
To wrogość.
Why didn't you run, then?
Więc czemu nie uciekłaś?
I was curious.
Byłam ciekawa.
I let it get the better of me.
Nie mogłam się powstrzymać.
Are there any others who support this decision?
Czy ktoś jeszcze popiera tę decyzję?
It is just us three.
Tylko nasza trójka.
Neither Hirokawa nor Gotou are aware.
Hirokawa i Gotou o niczym nie wiedzą.
I see.
Rozumiem. A co jest waszym argumentem?
My intuition.
Intuicja.
You will pose a great threat to us all in the future.
W przyszłości będziesz dla nas niebezpieczna.
I see.
Rozumiem.
You're like A.
Jesteś jak X.
"A"?
X?
We parasites behave and think in ways
My, pasożyty, myślimy logicznie
that are very logical and clear-cut.
i działamy bezpośrednio.
I had thought it would be easy enough for us to create a united organization,
Sądziłam, że bez trudu stworzymy zjednoczoną organizację,
but it appears I was wrong.
ale myliłam się.
However, it makes me happy to realize that parasites, myself included,
Jednak cieszę się, że pasożyty, w tym także ja,
have come to possess individual differences of this magnitude,
są w stanie różnić się tak między sobą
or should I say, individuality.
i wykazać się indywidualnością.
In fact, I am quite moved by your decision to lynch me.
Jestem wręcz poruszona, że postanowiliście mnie zlinczować.
Well, this is farewell, then.
A więc tutaj się pożegnamy.
Did you truly believe you could beat me if there were three of you?
Sądziliście, że pokonacie mnie w trójkę?
Don't let her get away!
Nie może uciec!
Kill her!
Zabić ją!
AUTHOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
AUTOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
THE ADVENTURE OF THE DYING DETECTIVE
PRZYGODA UMIERAJĄCEGO DETEKTYWA
My body's muscle strength exceeds yours.
Moje ciało jest silniejsze niż twoje.
Even in single combat, I would win.
Mógłbym pokonać cię nawet sam.
Ignorance is bliss.
Co za naiwność.
Not fast enough!
Jesteś za wolna.
You can keep that.
Możesz to zatrzymać.
Why did she split in two?
Czemu się rozdwoiła?
I'll go after her!
Biegnę za nią.
Tamura has entered his body?
Tamura wpełzła do jego ciała?
You okay?
Wszystko w porządku?
Yeah.
Tak.
There she is. That's her.
To ona.
Hey.
Hej!
Why are you putting pebbles in your bag?
- Czemu wkładasz kamienie do torebki? - Żeby chronić się przed zboczeńcami.
Sorry, we mistook you for someone else.
Przepraszamy, wzięliśmy cię za kogoś innego.
We saw this lady who only had half her head
Widzieliśmy kobietę, która miała tylko pół głowy.
and you're dressed the same as she was, so we just thought…
Była ubrana jak ty i pomyśleliśmy…
Half her head?
Pół głowy?
That's weird.
A to dziwne.
But my head's empty!
Za to moja głowa jest pusta.
She's beyond reason.
Tamura przestała myśleć racjonalnie.
Besides, I doubt half a parasite can maintain her bodily functions.
Zresztą myślę, że połowa pasożyta nie zdoła podtrzymać funkcji życiowych.
What she's doing is suicide.
To samobójstwo.
Pointless.
Bezcelowe.
Is this how Tamura Reiko, the one known for her intellect,
Tamura Reiko słynęła z intelektu,
will meet her end?
a zginie w taki sposób?
My legs! My lower body!
Moje nogi!
What are you doing?
Co robisz?
It's not me!
To nie ja.
One of us died?
Ktoś z nas zginął?
I see.
Rozumiem.
You can survive if you burrow inside.
Możesz przetrwać, jeśli wpełzniesz do środka.
But can you really take over when there's only half of you?
Ale czy zdołasz przetrwać, gdy jest cię tylko połowa?
Can you really win against me in that damaged body?
Myślisz, że możesz mnie pokonać w tym rannym ciele?
Stop!
Przestań!
It's my body!
To moje ciało!
Don't! Stop!
Nie! Przestań!
Who's speaking?
Kto teraz mówi?
Is it Hikawa?
Hikawa?
Or is it Tamura?
Czy Tamura?
Please stop!
Proszę, przestań! Jestem po twojej stronie!
If that's true, why are you approaching me?
To czemu się do mnie zbliżasz?
Shit! I've lost control of everything below my neck!
Straciłam kontrolę nad ciałem poniżej szyi.
Give it up!
Poddaj się.
Die along with that fragment of Tamura Reiko!
Zgiń razem z tym fragmentem Tamury Reiko.
I'm on your side!
Jestem po twojej stronie.
How dare you! How dare you?
Jak śmiesz?
How dare you?
Jak śmiesz?!
This is your strategy?
I to ma być twoja strategia?
The body you tried to take over is in shreds!
Ciało, które chciałaś opętać, jest w kawałkach.
Come out!
Wyjdź!
How long do you intend to hide in there?
Jak długo zamierzasz się tam chować?
When did you…
Kiedy…?
Given that our human bodies are our weakness,
Ludzkie ciała to nasz słaby punkt,
Even if our human bodies are destroyed,
Nawet po zniszczeniu ludzkich ciał
parasite cells continue to survive for a certain length of time
komórki pasożytnicze żyją jeszcze pewien czas
and emit signals,
i wysyłają sygnały,
as you are now experiencing firsthand.
czego właśnie doświadczacie.
The strongest signals we emit are animosity
Najsilniejsze sygnały, jakie wysyłamy, to wrogość
and our intent to kill.
i mordercze zamiary.
It is an important means of distinguishing
W ten sposób możemy określić,
whether a parasite we cannot see but can detect
czy pasożyt, którego tylko wyczuwamy,
is friend or foe.
jest przyjacielem czy wrogiem.
However, you decimated Hikawa's body despite her being an ally
Choć Hikawa była po waszej stronie, poszatkowałeś jej ciało,
and consequently spread fragments of flesh emanating animosity around you.
po czym miałeś wokół siebie kawałki emanujące wrogością.
That's right.
Tak.
Those fragments acted as camouflage
Te kawałki zamaskowały mój sygnał i pozwoliły mi się do ciebie zbliżyć.
Impossible.
Niemożliwe.
Even that was part of your plan?
Zaplanowałaś to?
Where have we come from? Where are we going?
Skąd pochodzimy? Dokąd zmierzamy?
Have you ever thought of such things, like a human might?
Myślałeś kiedyś o takich rzeczach niczym człowiek?
Goodbye, Kusano-san.
Żegnaj, Kusano-san.
Cannibalism, then…
To kanibalizm…
It's unlocked.
Otwarte.
TO MOTHER
DO MATKI BĄDŹ W HIKARI PARK 1 JUTRO O 17.00
You're more formidable than I'd thought, Detective.
Nie doceniałam pana, detektywie.
He left?
Wyszedł?
He's not staying at your hotel?
Nie ma go w waszym hotelu?
Dad?
Tata?
Why are you at home?
Co robisz w domu?
He hasn't been here.
Nie ma go tu.
Why are you there?
A ty co tam robisz?
Good morning.
Dzień dobry.
Are you there to kill him?
Chcesz go zabić?
I have no time for that.
Nie mam na to czasu.
I wanted to contact you regarding a personal matter.
Kontaktuję się z tobą w sprawie osobistej.
Do you know where Hikari Park 1 is?
Wiesz, gdzie jest Hikari Park 1?
I'd like you to be there today at 5:20 p.m.
Bądź tam dziś o 17.20.
What are you talking about?
O czym ty mówisz?
There's something I'd like to give you
Chcę ci coś dać,
because you're someone who's halfway between human and parasite.
ponieważ jesteś w połowie drogi między człowiekiem a pasożytem.
A mother, huh?
To jego matka?
Who are you?
Kim jesteś?
Ryoko. Where is Ryoko?
Gdzie jest Ryoko?
No one's home again.
Znowu nikogo nie ma w domu.
I wonder what's going on.
Co się dzieje?
You're Izumi-san, right?
Pani jest Izumi-san, prawda?
Where's Shinichi-kun?
Gdzie jest Shinichi-kun?
He's not here.
Nie ma go tu.
Oh… Are you his mother?
Jest pani jego matką?
No. Do I look that old to you?
Wyglądam aż tak staro?
Oh, no.
Nie.
Would you please tell me what happened?
Proszę mi powiedzieć, co się stało.
Isn't Shinichi-kun involved in something really dangerous?
Shinichi-kun jest wmieszany w coś niebezpiecznego?
Something really dangerous?
W coś niebezpiecznego?
I mean…
Widzę, że coś się dzieje.
Izumi-kun never says anything, but…
Izumi-kun nigdy nic nie mówi, ale…
I see you're worried about him.
Widzę, że się o niego martwisz.
I'm envious.
Zazdroszczę.
He's much tougher than he looks.
Jest twardszy, niż wygląda.
He'll come back soon, perfectly fine.
Niedługo wróci cały i zdrów.
When is "soon"?
Kiedy?
I've seen her somewhere before.
Już ją gdzieś widziałam.
I wonder where Izumi-kun's gone off to.
Ciekawe, gdzie jest Izumi-kun.
I can't believe his nerve. He has no idea how worried we are.
Nie ma pojęcia, jak się o niego martwimy.
He'll come back soon.
Niedługo wróci.
It might even be today.
Może nawet dzisiaj.
You'll come back, right?
Wrócisz, prawda?
He'll come back!
Wróci!
Hey.
Hej.
It's going to be okay. Don't worry.
Wszystko będzie dobrze. Nie martw się.
He'll come back.
Wróci.
I'm sure of it!
Jestem pewna!
What's wrong?
Co się stało?
Sorry! Go on without me!
Idźcie beze mnie!
I think this is where Kana-san lived.
To tu mieszkała Kana-san.
I wonder if Kana-san knew
Ciekawe, czy Kana-san
the things about Izumi-kun that I don't know.
wiedziała coś więcej o Izumi-kunie.
Hey, wait!
Czekaj!
Dammit, she's so quick on her feet!
Cholera, ale jest szybka!
Hey!
No nie!
Don't do that!
To nie przystoi, by młoda dama tak głośno przeklinała.
TO MOTHER, COME TO HIKARI PARK 1 TOMORROW AT 5 PM. DETECTIVE SHERLOCK HOLMES
DO MATKI
What's this?
A to co?
Oh, there.
Już, już.
Peek-a-boo!
A kuku!
You're good with babies.
Masz rękę do dzieci.
My wife was the breadwinner for a time.
Przez pewien czas utrzymywała nas żona.
I did a lot of babysitting.
Opiekowałem się wtedy dzieckiem.
There.
Już, już.
Peek-a-boo!
A kuku!
I got here too early.
Jestem za wcześnie.
Then walk around.
Przejdź się po okolicy.
I'd like to check out the terrain.
Chcę się rozejrzeć.
All right.
Dobrze.
HIKARI PARK 1
HIKARI PARK 1
So, even a cold-blooded monster values her own child.
Więc nawet bezwzględny potwór troszczy się o swoje dziecko.
I have been researching humans.
Bacznie przyglądałam się ludziom.
I can somewhat understand your irrational behavior.
Poniekąd rozumiem wasze irracjonalne zachowanie.
That's good to hear.
Cieszę się.
But you still can't understand!
Ale jednego wciąż nie rozumiesz.
You don't know what it means to be human.
Nie wiesz, co to znaczy być człowiekiem. o to znaczy być rodzicem.
The enormity of the happiness you've created for yourself in your life!
Nie wiesz, jakie szczęście daje rodzina
The crushing weight of grief when you've lost everything!
i jaką czujesz rozpacz, kiedy ją tracisz.
None of you know!
Nikt z was tego nie wie.
Even if I killed this baby right here and now,
Gdybym zabił teraz to dziecko,
you wouldn't grieve.
nie opłakiwałabyś go.
You'd just think, "Oh, okay."
Nie przejęłabyś się.
Am I wrong?
Mam rację?
Besides, this is not your baby.
Poza tym to nie jest twoje dziecko.
It is a human baby.
To ludzkie dziecko.
What is this?
A to co?
I've never sensed such a signal coming from one of my kind.
Pierwszy raz czuję taki sygnał.
It is Tamura Reiko, but…
To Tamura Reiko, ale…
What is this emotion?
Co to za emocja?
You'll never understand.
Nigdy nie zrozumiesz.
You just can't.
To dla ciebie niemożliwe.
But if you could at least experience one iota of the grief I've felt…
Gdybyś choć po części mogła poczuć moją rozpacz…
It was just a joke.
To był blef.
As if a human could kill a human baby.
Człowiek nie mógłby tak zabić dziecka.
Who knew that a monster like you would…
Kto by pomyślał, że taki potwór jak ty może…
What a surprise.
Co za niespodzianka.
I'm surprised myself.
Sama jestem zaskoczona.
Tamura Reiko is on the move.
Tamura Reiko porusza się.
She's headed for the opposite corner.
Zmierza do przeciwległego końca.
So she's coming this way.
Czyli idzie tutaj.
Seriously, what am I doing, coming all the way out here?
Czemu ja tu przyszłam?
There's…
Tam ktoś jest!
Kuramori!
Kuramori!
Kuramori! Hey, hang in there!
Kuramori! Trzymaj się!
Oh, Detective.
Detektywie…
Are they here?
Czy oni tam są?
Go!
Idźcie!
If you identify one on sight, don't hesitate!
Jeśli ich zobaczycie, nie wahajcie się!
Yes, sir!
Tak jest!
It was Tamura Reiko, wasn't it?
To była Tamura Reiko, prawda? Była sama?
Does Hirokawa not know?
Hirokawa nic nie wie?
She's wearing white, holding a baby.
Jest ubrana na biało. Ma na rękach dziecko.
The baby's clothes have some of my blood on them.
Jego ubranko jest poplamione krwią.
Got it! We won't let her get away!
Nie damy jej uciec.
Tell me one more thing!
Powiedz mi jeszcze jedno.
The "partner" you spoke of in your report, who is it?
Kim jest ten partner, którego wspomniałeś w raporcie?
Is he human?
To człowiek?
Tell me his name!
Jak się nazywa?
He's a human being.
To człowiek.
Like me, he had a small family.
Miał małą rodzinę, jak ja.
It was taken away from him.
Została mu odebrana.
He suffered pain.
Cierpiał.
Please! Tell me his name!
Jak się nazywa?
Youko.
Youko.
Yumi.
Yumi.
I'm sorry.
Przepraszam.
I'll be with you soon.
Niedługo będę z wami.
Kuramori-san?
Kuramori-san?
Stay with me, Kuramori-san!
Zostań ze mną!
I'm glad I didn't kill the baby.
Cieszę się, że nie zabiłem tego dziecka.
Hey! Kuramori-san!
Kuramori-san!
Kuramori!
Kuramori!
You did well.
Dobrze się spisałeś.
You may even become a hero after all this is over!
Gdy będzie po wszystkim, być może okrzykną cię bohaterem.
I will avenge your death, Detective!
Pomszczę twoją śmierć, detektywie!
-Understood! -White clothes and a baby.
- Przyjąłem. - Białe ubranie i dziecko.
What's your name?
Jak się nazywasz?
Answer me, now!
Odpowiadaj!
I pray Hirokawa's group has no idea what we're up to!
Oby grupa Hirokawy nie wiedziała, co zamierzamy.
We cannot let Tamura Reiko get away!
Tamura Reiko nie może uciec!
We have to finish her now!
Musimy ją wykończyć!
Next time, "More than Human."
Następny odcinek: „Więcej niż człowiek”